We've seen that the reinforcement learning framework gives us a way to study
我们了解到 强化学习框架使我们能够研究
how an agent can learn to accomplish a goal from interacting with its environment.
智能体如何通过与环境互动实现目标
This framework works for many real world applications and simplifies
这种框架适合很多现实应用
the interaction into three signals that are passed between agent and environment.
并将互动简化为在智能体和环境之间传递的三种信号
The state signal is the environment's way of presenting a situation to the agent.
状态信号是环境向智能体呈现情形的方式
The agent then responds with an action which influences the environment.
智能体然后做出动作响应并影响到环境
And the environment responds with the reward which gives
环境做出奖励响应
some indication of whether the agent has responded appropriately to the environment.
表示智能体是否对环境做出了正确响应
Also built into the framework is the agent's goal which is to maximize cumulative reward.
该框架还包括智能体目标 即最大化累积奖励
But what exactly does this mean and how does the agent accomplish this?
这到底是什么意思 智能体如何实现这一目标？
Towards its goal, what do you think?
朝着该目标前进是什么意思？
Could the agent just maximize the reward and each time step?
智能体可以只在每个时间步最大化奖励吗？
The short answer to that question is, no.
简短答案是不可以
But I think a long answer would be a lot more satisfying.
但是我认为可能需要更详细的答案
So let's try to understand this with the walking robot example.
我们用步行机器人作为讲解示例
Remember that in this case,
注意 对于此示例
the goal of the robot was to stay walking forward for as
机器人的目标是尽量向前行走很长的时间
long and as quickly as possible while also exerting minimal effort.
并且速度很快 同时表现得很自然 不用卖力行走
In this case, if the robot tried to
如果机器人尝试在单个时间步
maximize the reward it received at a single time step,
最大化收到的奖励
that would look like trying to move as quickly as possible with
则是尝试尽量快速移动 动作自然
as little effort without falling immediately.
并且不会立即摔倒
That could work well in the short term but it's possible, for instance,
短期内效果很好
that the agents movement gets it moving quickly without falling initially.
但是如果智能体快速移动 一开始不会摔倒
But that first movement was de-stabilising
但是前面的动作使得机器人不够稳定
enough that it doomed the agent to fall in a short time.
导致很快就会摔倒
In this way, if the agent focused on individual time steps,
这样的话 如果智能体侧重于单个时间步的目标
it could learn actions that maximize initial rewards.
它会学习最大化初始奖励的动作
But then the episode terminates quite quickly.
但是这一阶段很快就会结束
And so the cumulative reward is quite small.
因此累积奖励很小
And still worse, in this case,
更糟糕的是
the agent will not have learned to walk.
智能体将无法学会行走
In this example then,
在此示例中
it's clear that the agent cannot focus on individual time steps and instead,
很明显智能体不能侧重于单个时间步
needs to keep all time steps in mind.
而是需要考虑所有时间步
But this also holds true for reinforcement learning agents in general.
一般的强化学习智能体也是这样
Actions have short and long term consequences and the agent needs
动作有短期后果和长期后果
to gain some understanding of the complex effects its actions have on the environment.
智能体需要了解动作对环境的复杂影响
Along these lines in the walking robot example,
对于步行机器人示例
the agent always has reward at all time steps in mind,
智能体始终考虑所有时间步的奖励
it will learn to choose movement designed for long term stability.
它将学会选择实现长期稳定性的动作
So in this way, the robot moves a bit slowly to sacrifice a little bit of reward
这样的话 机器人会稍微移动得慢些 并牺牲一点点的奖励
but it will payoff because it will avoid falling for
但是这样会有回报 因为它可以更长时间地避免摔倒
longer and collect higher cumulative reward.
并收集更高的累积奖励
But now, what does all of this mean when the agent
但是 这对智能体在随机时间步
chooses an action at an arbitrary time step?
选择动作来说有什么意义
How exactly does it keep all time steps in mind?
它是如何记录所有时间步的
Well, if we're looking at some time step, t,
对于时间步 t
it's important to note that the rewards for
需要注意的是 所有之前时间步的奖励已经确定了
all previous time steps have already been decided as they're in the past.
因为它们是过去的奖励
Only future rewards are inside the agent's control.
只有未来的奖励受到智能体的控制
We refer to the sum of rewards from the next time step
我们将后续时间步的奖励之和
onward as the return and denote it with a capital G,
称之为回报 表示为 G
and at an arbitrary time step,
在任何随机时间步
the agent will always choose an action towards the goal of maximizing the return.
智能体将始终选择一个目标是最大化回报的动作
But it's actually more accurate to say that the agent seeks to maximize expected return.
更准确的说法是 智能体的目标是最大化预期回报
This is because it's generally the case that the agent can't
因为通常智能体无法完全肯定地预测
predict with complete certainty what the future reward is likely to be.
未来奖励会怎样
So it has to rely on a prediction or an estimate.
它必须依赖于预测或估算
We'll massage this a bit when we talk about discounted return.
当我们讨论折扣回报时 将稍微讲解这一概念
But this is the main idea.
这就是主要概念